Liaison rule three, vowel, vowel. When a word ending in a vowel sound is next to
one beginning with a vowel sound, they're connected with a glide between the two
vowels. A glide is either a slight Y sound or a slight W sound. How do you know which
one to use? This will take care of itself. The position your lips are in will dictate
either Y or W. Go away, I also need the other one. For example, if a word ends in
O, lips are going to be in the forward position, so a W quite naturally leads
into the next vowel sound, go away. You don't want to say go away and break the
undercurrent of your voice. Run it all together, go away. After a long E sound,
your lips will be pulled back far enough to create a Y glide or liaison. I also
need the other one. Don't force this too much though. It's not really a strong
pushing sound. I also need the other one would sound really weird.